<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>DBMS - Tag - Debakar Roy</title>
        <link>http://debakarr.github.io/tags/dbms/</link>
        <description>DBMS - Tag - Debakar Roy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://debakarr.github.io/tags/dbms/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>[Training] DBMS with Oracle Day 5</title>
    <link>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-5/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Debakar Roy</author>
    <guid>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-5/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This time I am a bit late. Actually, my college started so it took me some time to write-up my next blog post. Anyways, today we are going to have a look at PL/SQL Cursor, Procedure, Function, and Trigger. This will complete the very basics of PL/SQL.
So what is cursor?
Cursor is a pointer to a memory area called context area(Actually it is a pointer to a row). Whenever you use SELECT or any DML (INSERT, DELETE, UPDATE or MERGE) then cursor holds the rows (one or more) returned by a SQL statement.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Training] DBMS with Oracle Day 4</title>
    <link>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-4/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Debakar Roy</author>
    <guid>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-4/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If you are reading this then I want to notify you that this is the 3rd part of the series of blog post I am writing up about basically DBMS with Oracle.
If you haven&rsquo;t yet read my previous post then feel free to go to this link for part 1 and this link for part 2.
Now today we are going to look at something called PL/SQL and also we will do some exercise to get a grip of PL/SQL.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Training] DBMS with Oracle Day 3</title>
    <link>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-3/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Debakar Roy</author>
    <guid>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So in this blog basically we are going to cover up the things done by me on the second day of my Oracle DBMS Training. Although I am not going to use the same schema I used during the 2nd day of my training.
So without further delay, lets dig in.
First thing first. What is a schema?
This is something I should have mentioned in the first blog. In general, a schema is a set of tables, sproc(stored procedure) and other objects that make up a whole database.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Training] DBMS with Oracle Day 1</title>
    <link>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Debakar Roy</author>
    <guid>http://debakarr.github.io/posts/oracle-dbms-day-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this post, I am going to wrap up all the things I learned during my first class on &lsquo;DBMS with Oracle&rsquo;. The training lecture is given by &lsquo;Rahul Sohal&rsquo;, CTO &amp; Resource Management Lead of iandwe.in.
So first of all what is database?
A database is a collection of information kept an organized way, for the ease of retrieval.
Facebook has its own database. Think about yesterday when you logged in your account and like all those posts, share certain stuff, commented on a picture.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
